[Recording]
Time flies,
and the years slip by.
We've known each other for ten years now.
In this fleeting stretch of time,
you've given me endless warmth
and made my life so much better.
Xia Xue,
will you marry me?
[THE GUILTY]
[Episode 3]
[Sancheng Financial Services]
We turned Nanping
upside down—
hair salons,
mahjong parlors,
docks, bus stations, hotels,
KTVs—
every corner.
And still, we couldn't find Ma Derong.
Hello. Police. Is Lu Ming here?
Have a seat.
Who would want to be a lighthouse keeper?
There's not a soul here.
It's so desolate.
We'll know when we're up there.
Lin Hua, do you remember me?
Of course.
Long time no see.
It's been ten years, hasn't it?
Have a seat.
Smoke?
No, thanks.
You're Officer Qin Wen.
I remember you.
You have a good memory.
I'll get straight to the point.
I'm here today
mainly about
a case involving Xia Xue.
I have a few questions for you.
Do you know that Xia Xue has a daughter
named Hou Shanshan?
No.
Hou Shanshan is missing.
Missing?
You should go look for her,
not me.
Then you must have no idea
who Hou Shanshan's father is, right?
Well, obviously. If she's a Hou,
her dad must be one, too.
Lin Hua,
let me remind you.
This is no longer
a simple child kidnapping case.
It now involves intentional homicide.
Judging by Hou Shanshan's age,
Xia Xue would have still
been in a relationship with you
at the time of the birth.
Officer Qin.
What does that mean?
You can't just say things like that.
How about this?
You go ask Xia Xue.
Whoever she names is the father,
but I'm not taking the fall for this.
Why did you break up later?
We were actually getting along quite well.
But then, something happened
with her family.
People change,
you know.
She wanted someone reliable,
someone with a career.
I understand that.
Xia Xue married a rich guy.
And Lu Ming
started a company.
I'm just a lighthouse keeper.
You can see that.
Our lives don't intersect anymore.
So what's there to contact?
Lu Ming.
I remember back then,
you were a student
at Huacheng University,
majoring in Law, right?
What made you change paths
and do a job like this?
What's wrong with it?
I'm just making a living.
Besides,
this is a legitimate business.
Don't get upset.
We aren't here today
to investigate your business.
We just want to ask about Hou Shanshan.
Well, even if we're not
talking business,
surely you won't deny us
a simple glass of water?
Here.
Thank you.
Thanks.
You were pretty sharp.
Could Lu Ming have killed Wang Bingkun?
I don't know.
The silhouette looks like him.
Run a DNA test,
and we'll know.
[Sancheng Financial Services]
Lin Hua.
I think if you
still consider them friends,
you'd better tell us the truth.
I will.
That's the only way we can
help Xia Xue find her child faster
and clear Lu Ming of suspicion.
What suspicion?
Lin Hua lied.
He must still be in contact with them.
And did you notice?
When we brought up
Lu Ming and Xia Xue,
Lin Hua's reaction
was unnatural,
as if he was desperate
to hide some kind of truth.
[Lin's Repairs]
And I discovered an important clue.
Their statements
are surprisingly consistent.
They all avoided talking
about Hou Shanshan's biological father.
Let's head back to the Bureau.
[Lin's Repairs]
Yes.
[1999]
Kai.
Guess what?
Xia Gang
moved all the fire extinguishers
in the office.
Then find something else for him to do.
I'm way ahead of you.
I made him copy down the...
vehicle entry and exit logs.
He can't leave until he's done.
What's wrong?
You're still not satisfied?
Did you deliver the car?
Yes.
How's the dealership doing lately?
Really well.
Those cars we flipped
are selling really well.
Of course, it's all because
of your reputation.
We've sold three this week.
If your dad knew
you were making money like this,
he'd be thrilled.
You think my dad would be happy?
Definitely.
It's yours now. I just bought it.
What have Xia Xue
and that college boy of hers been up to?
[Motorbike]
Kai.
Do you have a thing for her?
I was just kidding.
Gotta go. Tonight, Jinlong Food Stall.
Over there.
That's a lot of people.
Of course.
This tree's really something.
Many big bosses
come here to pray every year.
So, when you returned to Nanping,
we should have come here first
and prayed.
Maybe then,
we wouldn't have had such bad luck.
Yeah.
We should have listened to Lin Hua.
I didn't hear about it
a couple of years ago.
Auntie.
Don't throw this. Give it to us.
Right.
Give it to us.
Lin Hua.
Look, our offering
stands out from the rest.
When the gods see
how different we are,
they'll take care of our business first.
If it doesn't work, I'm coming for you.
Okay, okay.
Gods, please bless
Lu Ming and Xia Xue with a baby soon.
If you're gonna pray,
pray for the three of us—
together.
Then here's to everything going smoothly,
and to staying safe and sound.
Okay.
Smooth and safe.
What are you wishing for?
It's taking so long.
-Just having a heart-to-heart with him.
-Tell me. I’ll listen.
Forget it.
What's in your heart?
It won't work if I say it out loud.
Probably it is still about having a baby.
You...
Don't talk nonsense.
Seriously,
what did you guys wish for?
I can't tell you.
Just a small wish.
Young Mr. Ma.
What took you so long?
Cook some noodles for me later.
Dad.
Didn't you say
you were coming back tomorrow?
You've gained some weight.
You're back early today.
It's the usual time.
Did you miss me?
I heard
you're looking for someone
to deal with a policewoman at the station.
Do you need my help?
No.
Have a seat.
Sit.
Here's my plan.
I'll start at her place...
I'm warning you.
Stay away from the police.
I've investigated her.
-She has no background.
-Our company is in the middle of a reorg.
Don't let your actions
ruin the big picture.
Do you hear me?
Yes, yes.
Go.
Go to your room.
There's a gift.
We'll talk about the policewoman later.
Where is it?
Dad, I love you so much!
All shifts and teams,
get your fire extinguishers.
Take them back and check them carefully.
If any are damaged, come back
and exchange them immediately.
Here.
You're here, Young Mr. Ma.
[Sign-in Log]
Should we get started?
Why don't you take your men
to check first?
I still need to see Qiu.
[Ma Kai]
Okay.
You just take your men and check.
Are these fire extinguishers new?
Yes.
Xia from the Security Department
just replaced them.
They're so dirty,
and you call them new?
Young Mr. Ma.
New or old, they work the same.
Just replaced, huh?
Young Mr. Ma, what are you doing?
These are all new.
Just replaced.
None of your business.
You can't use them now, can you?
You said the fire equipment
is Xia Gang's responsibility
from the Security Department, right?
Yes, Young Mr. Ma.
Handle this strictly.
Don't be grinning all day long.
Go on with the check.
What are you waiting for?
Move them, quickly.
Rose, rose, so fair and sweet.
You sing terribly.
You sing then.
Go ahead.
You sing.
I sing even worse.
Alright.
What is this?
This is the DV
I borrowed from the shipyard.
Why did you borrow a DV?
Of course we have to record
such an important day.
Why is it important?
Today is Lin Hua's
first day using a walking stick.
We have to record it.
Right.
Let's go.
Indeed.
Look at there.
What?
There's a bird.
A butterfly.
Wow, it is.
Go.
Lin Hua.
Come on.
Are you okay?
I'm fine.
Let me help you.
Why help me?
I'm not an old man.
Why don't we take a break?
Yeah.
Let's rest here.
Lin Hua, what do you think?
You two rest.
I'm not tired.
I'll keep going.
I'll wait for you at the top.
Go follow him.
Have some water first.
You really won't rest?
Why rest?
If I rest,
it'll be dark before you can propose.
Yeah, yeah.
I still have to change into my suit later.
Remember to find a good angle.
Okay, I know.
You've said it a hundred times.
I'll make sure Xia Xue looks stunning
and you look handsome in these shots.
Hurry up.
I'll carry you.
Can you do it?
Yes.
One, two.
So slow. I walk faster than this.
Almost there.
I can't go on. I can't go on.
Let's stop here. Right here.
Alright, stop looking.
Let's get to work.
-Well. Stand there and don't move.
-What are you doing?
Let me see
where you two will look best.
Move a bit to the left.
Okay, right there.
Right here.
That's good.
Xia Xue will stand here later.
Then you just say what you prepared—
"Time flies,
and years pass,"
and Xia Xu will say, "I do."
Alright, alright.
I still need to change into my suit.
I'll record a bit
for later use.
Recording now.
Capturing some precious moments for you.
Why is she still halfway up?
Did we walk that fast?
Lin Hua.
Something doesn't feel right.
Let's go down and check.
Okay.
Xia Xue!
Split up.
Unfortunately.
I'm in a bad mood today.
But coincidentally,
you all seem to be in a good mood, huh?
[Recording]
Looks like...
it is the shipyard...
There's an explosion!
There are injuries.
There are people still inside.
Quick! Team One, secure the perimeter.
Don't let anyone in.
Team Two, bring detectors
and check for gas leaks.
There are still people inside.
Help save the people now.
And compile the casualty list.
Has Mr. Ma been notified?
Yes.
He's on his way.
Where is Young Mr. Ma?
Ma Kai? Where is Ma Kai?
We haven't found him yet.
Everyone, leave this area
as soon as possible.
Hurry up and find him!
Hello.
The number you dialed
is temporarily unavailable.
We now interrupt our program
for breaking news.
An explosion has occurred
at Nanping Xijiang Shipyard.
Fire and medical teams have arrived
at the scene
of the Nanping Xijiang Shipyard explosion
to conduct rescue operations.
At the site of the explosion,
authorities have implemented
temporary traffic controls
on surrounding roads
to ensure clear access for rescue efforts.
Relevant departments have established
an emergency response command center
-Turn up the volume! -to coordinate
rescue and medical treatment,
and the investigation into the cause of
the incident and follow-up arrangements.
As of the time of this report,
the cause of the explosion
remains unknown,
and casualties are still being assessed.
We will continue to follow developments
at the Nanping Xijiang Shipyard
and bring you updates
as they become available.
[Police]
Come on.
They need more hands over there.
Another one's dead.
Hurry up and carry the body over.
Bring it here?
Yes.
There's another victim here.
Zhao Guang!
Hurry up!
Chen Adi!
Hurry.
Tian Wen!
Hurry up.
There are two more bodies here.
Be careful.
Move the injured over there.
Okay.
Are there many injured inside?
Yes.
You go first.
I've got this. Leave it to me.
Everyone, be careful.
Come on.
Watch out.
Be careful.
Xia Gang!
Make way.
Ma Kai!
[2010]
[Police Investigation Area]
Captain Qin,
the results are in.
After DNA
comparison,
the tissue under Wang Bingkun's nails
doesn't belong to Lu Ming.
He's not related to Hou Shanshan, either.
He's not her father.
Let's go.
[Hou Jun] [Couple] [Xia Xue]
Xia Xue.
We didn't ask you to meet at home,
but asked you here instead.
I hope you understand our intentions.
We just want you
to relax, let go of all your concerns,
and be honest with us.
Don't worry. We will protect your privacy.
I hope you can tell us the truth.
We met ten years ago.
[Police Office Operating Procedures]
You're Ma Kai, right?
I didn't tell Hou Jun about this.
I don't want to cause
unnecessary misunderstandings
between you two.
Thanks for your consideration.
Actually, you could have told him.
Hou Jun and I have been married for years.
We don't have many secrets.
Ma Kai!
His face was charred.
How can you be sure?
Most of the body was charred.
We've cross-referenced them
with the entry logs,
and
all the names match up.
[Ma Kai]
You asked about
the child's biological father.
What does that have to do
with finding my child?
It matters. It matters a lot.
If this isn't a standard kidnapping
for ransom,
it's very likely the child
was taken by her biological father,
or
a revenge hit
by one of his enemies.
We've seen many cases like this.
That's why I asked
who the biological father is,
but you refused to answer.
It's alright.
We've already traced it to Lu Ming.
Lu Ming and I...
did have a history.
But the child isn't his.
The kidnapping...
has nothing to do with him.
As for her biological father,
that was just a mistake made in my youth.
You two grew up together.
So you mean,
because of that mistake you made,
you broke up with Lu Ming?
It's not exactly something to be proud of.
If you were me, would you talk about it?
I'll go turn myself in.
We can't hide this.
I'll take the blame.
Ma Kai is Ma Derong's son.
Do you think he'll let this go?
What if he tries to hurt Xia Xue?
That's why I'm turning myself in.
What will happen to Xia Xue if you do?
She needs you now more than ever.
Even if you want to turn yourself in,
you need to make sure Xia Xue is settled.
Uncle Xia hasn't been laid to rest yet.
Xia Xue.
Every minute you delay,
Shanshan is in danger for another minute.
This concerns Shanshan's safety.
So, I hope you'll seriously consider
telling us the whole truth. Alright?
I have nothing to hide.
Well,
where is the DV you brought here?
♪ Crying in the morning ♪
♪ Tears stay ♪
♪ Oh my sleeve ♪
The police didn't just come to us.
♪ Retreating without warning ♪
They also went to Xia Xue.
They kept asking
about the child's background.
♪ Would that keep on forming? ♪
♪ Eyes low; can't believe ♪
Do you have any news about her?
Don't rush. Take your time looking.
Don't rush.
♪ Time won't stay ♪
♪ Dreams decay ♪
♪ Karma spins a thread we can't unweave ♪
No.
Is it here?
It should be right here.
♪ Time won't stay ♪
♪ Dreams decay ♪
Why is it gone?
Could someone have picked it up?
♪ Karma spins a thread we can't unweave ♪
If someone picked it up,
the body might also be found.
♪ Oh ♪
♪ The thread won't shape
the soul I became ♪
We have to hurry
♪ Don't look back my way ♪
♪ I won't hear your name ♪
♪ Let the voice start to fade ♪
♪ I won't play your wicked game ♪
♪ Can't go forward; can't go back ♪
♪ Only stay and break ♪
♪ Oh ♪
♪ I won't take the blame ♪
♪ Won't be drawn by fame ♪
♪ Oh ♪
♪ The thread won't shape
the soul I became ♪
♪ Don't look back my way ♪
♪ I won't hear your name ♪
♪ Let the voice start to fade ♪
♪ I won't play your wicked game ♪
♪ Can't go forward; can't go back ♪
♪ Only stay and break ♪